Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Frederick William MacMonnies papers
- Mary Smart's Research Files, 1908-1997, Series 8:; (Box 2-6, 9; 4.2 linear feet)
  - West Family History, undated, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 19-22)
  - West Point Battle Monument, 1970-1976, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
  - James McNeill Whistler, 1977-1994, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 25-28)
  - Stanford White, 1966-1981, (3 folders; oversized Material Housed in Box 9) (Box 5, Folder 29-33)
  - General John Blackburne Woodward Monument, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Writings - Critical, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Yearly Summaries, undated, (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 36-41)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies Through 1885, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1886-1887, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1891, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1892, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1893, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1894, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1896, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1897, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1898, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 51-52)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1899, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1900, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1901, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1902, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1903, undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1904, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1905-1907, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1908-1909, undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1910, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 61-62)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1911, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1912, undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1913, undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1914, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1915, undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1916, undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1917, undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1918-1919, undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1920-1922, undated (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1925, undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1926, undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1927-1929, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies in 1931-1936, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Material Concerning MacMonnies After 1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1977-1988, (9 folders; oversized Material Housed in Box 9) (Box 6, Folder 4-12)
  - Miscellaneous Copies Used in Book, 1995, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 13-16)
  - Miscellaneous Copies For Possible Use in the Book, 1901-1995, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 17-21)
  - Bibliography of Other Sources Used by Mary Smart But Not Listed in Book, 1966-1989, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 22-26)
  - Oversized Calendar Containing Photographs of Monet's House at Giverny, 1993, (from Box 4, Folder 25) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Clippings Concerning Stanford White, 1966-1981, (from Box 5, Folder 33) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Two Oversized Calendar Pages, 1981, (from Box 6, Folder 1) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Printed Material, 1896-1996, Series 9:; (Box 6-7; 13 folders)
  Printed material includes clippings, a brochure concerning reproductions issued by the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, and a copy of Mary Smart's book A Flight With Fame.
  - Clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1896-1902 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1904-1906 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1907-1909 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1912-1913 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1914, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
  - Clippings, 1921-1936 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1941-1946 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Brochure of Reproductions Issued by the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Biography of MacMonnies A Flight With Fame by Mary Smart, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Photographs, 1889-1911, Series 10:; (Box 7, 9; 8 folders)
  Photographs are of Frederick MacMonnies seated in front of the clay model of his statue General Henry Warner Slocum, and of MacMonnies with second wife Alice Jones in Lucerne, Switzerland immediately following their wedding. There are also photographs of family members including his parents, his first wife Mary Fairchild MacMonnies at the easel, his children, exterior views of his studio,a unique image of a horse being posed for use as a model for The Horse Tamers, and of art work.
  - Photographs of Frederick MacMonnies, 1900-1910 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of MacMonnies Family Members, 1901-1909, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Photographs of the Exterior of MacMonnies' Studio, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Photograph of a Horse Used as a Model for Sculpture The Horse Tamers, 1894 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Art Work by MacMonnies: Sculpture, 1889-1911, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 9) (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Photographs of Art Work by MacMonnies: Paintings, 1901-1902 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Five Oversized Photographs of Sculpture by MacMonnies, 1889-1911, (from Box 7, Folders 11-12) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Photograph of Mural by Mary Fairchild MacMonnies Low, 1893 (Box 9, Folder 5)